Guide to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello RG.006
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series IX: Photographs, 5720; 0 Linear Feet
  - Commencement, 1975, 7040 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Commencement, 1987, 7041 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Commencement, Misc., 1983-1988; 7042 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Paul Hallingby's Dinner, 1987; 7043 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Slovenia with Virginia Bugliarello, 1989; 7044 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Poly Overnight for New Students ("Club Poly"), 1990s; 7045 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1992, 7046 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Raduno Internazionale dei Giuliano-Dalmati, 1993; 7047 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Brussels, 1997, 7048 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990s, 1991-1999; 7049 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Vancouver with Dr. Lang, undated; 7050 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Photos from All Day Meeting, undated; 7051 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 7052 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974, 7103 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1974, 1976, 7104 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Commencement - Honorary degrees, 1974, 7105 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Bombay, 1974, 7106 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - National Federation of the Italian-American Society, circa 1974; 7107 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Helen Lee, 1975; 7108 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Unveiling Ernst Weber's Portrait, 1976; 7109 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Association's 113th Dinner Dance, 1976; 7110 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Eugene and Estelle Kone, 1976; 7111 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990s, 7112 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Westchester Polytechnic Dinner, 1991; 7113 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Campus Development Plan, 1981; 7114 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music, 1982; 7115 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Herman Mark and Hans Mark, 1983-1984; 7116 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Ed Koch, 1984; 7117 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985, 7118 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Howard Golden, 1985; 7119 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Rome, 1986; 7120 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - 16th Pacific Congress, Seoul, 1987; 7121 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - National Academy of Engineering, 1987; 7122 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Governor Mario Cuomo, 1988; 7123 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Argonne National Laboratory, 1990; 7124 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Venice, 1990; 7125 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - University of Utah Christmas Party, 1991; 7126 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Photo and clipping from Paul Bruins, 1992; 7127 (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Instituto Dermopatico Dell'Immacolata, 1992; 7128 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Mayor Rudolph Guiliani, 1994; 7129 (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Events, 1975-1995, 7130 (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Event, undated, 7131 (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Citizen Nyembo, Poly and Zaire, undated; 7132 (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Marconi Award, undated; 7133 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - MetroTech and Mayor Koch, 1990s; 7134 (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966, Undated, 7135 (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - Dibner Library - Oversize, 1990; 7136 (Box 46.1, Folder 1)
  - Rome - Oversize, 1984; 7137 (Box 46.1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous 1975 - Oversize, 7138 (Box 46.1, Folder 3)
  - Photo album with clippings and articles, 1951-1960; 7139 (Box 46.1, Volume 1)
- Series X: Early Career, 1958-1979; 5736
  This series contains materials from George Bugliarello's educational and professional career prior to his appointment as University President in 1973 and includes mostly correspondence from his time as student and research assistant at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (1956-1959), professor at Carnegie Mellon University (1959-1966) and professor and Dean of Engineering at University of Illinois at Chicago Circle (1969-1973).
  This series is arranged semi-chronologically by institution (MIT, Carnegie-Mellon University, and University of Illinois at Chicago Circle).
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology – Sigma Xi Membership, 1958; 5765 (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Correspondence, Publications, 1960-1962; 5764 (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Correspondence, Publications, 1963; 5763 (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Publications- "Health Care Needs and Prototype Plans.." – Project Director, 1968 October 1; 5761 (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Professor T.E. Unny, University of Waterloo – Correspondence, 1969; 5748 (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University – Dr. Michael H. Weissman – RESTRICT, 1970 September; 5749 (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - Professor Iraj Zandi – Correspondence, 1970; 5738 (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - Dr. R.H.J. Sellin – Correspondence, 1973 June; 5739 (Box 46, Folder 41)
  - Jane Shaw – McGraw Publications – Correspondence, 1970 November; 5740 (Box 46, Folder 42)
  - Proposal for a Research Center for Environmental Engineering Systems and Communications – George Bugliarello, 1966 February 1; 5758 (Box 46, Folder 43)
  - Professor William M. Siebert – MIT – Correspondence, 1971 June-July; 5741 (Box 46, Folder 44)
  - Notebook – "Rivers and Harbors (Summary) Geo. Bugliarello – V.A.T.Y., Undated; 5757 (Box 46, Folder 45)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program, 1969; 5750 (Box 46, Folder 46)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – "U" Miscellaneous, 1969-1970; 5754 (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – "W" Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969-1973; 5747 (Box 46, Folder 48)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – University of Utah International Symposium on Human Ecology, 1970; 5755 (Box 46, Folder 49)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Science Magazine, 1970 August; 5743 (Box 46, Folder 50)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Brian Guy Rice – RESTRICT, 1970-1973; 5756 (Box 46, Folder 51)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – George Yanizeski, 1971; 5737 (Box 46, Folder 52)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Richmond College, Consulting committee, 1971; 5751 (Box 46, Folder 53)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Richmond College, Consulting Committee – Syllabi, 1971; 5752 (Box 46, Folder 54)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Office of Business Affairs – Salaries – RESTRICT, 1971; 5759 (Box 46, Folder 55)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Engineering Law Seminar, 1971-1972; 5753 (Box 46, Folder 56)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – International Journal of Social Technology – Editorial Advisory Board, 1972-1973; 5745 (Box 46, Folder 57)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Professor Jeremy Robinson, 1973 June; 5742 (Box 46, Folder 58)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Conference on the Applications of Undergraduate Mathematics – Paper Manuscript, 1973; 5762 (Box 46, Folder 59)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – World Development, 1973; 5744 (Box 46, Folder 60)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Dr. Noel Vietmeyer, 1973; 5746 (Box 46, Folder 61)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle – Correspondence, 1979; 5760 (Box 46, Folder 62)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago and Carnegie-Mellon University ("Dean's Personal File"), 1966 May - 1969 October; 7144 (Box 46, Folder 63)
  - Univerisity of Illinois at Chicago and Carnegie-Mellon University ("Dean's Personal File"), 1969 November- 1971 May; 7145 (Box 46, Folder 64)
- Series XI: Addendum I, 5735
  This addendum to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello consists of 3 Paige boxes (3.75 linear feet) of unsorted material from the President's office pre-dating George Bugliarello's appointment as University President and includes correspondence, departmental reports, course syllabi, and professors' notes. These documents require additional processing.
  - Pre-Bugliarello - Unsorted, Undated; 5811 (Box 47)
  - Pre-Bugliarello - Unsorted, Undated; 5812 (Box 48)
  - Pre-Bugliarello - Unsorted, Undated; 5813 (Box 49)
- Series XII: Addendum II, 7151
  Addendum II is arranged in following subseries that mirror the main series of the collection:
  The arrangement of this series mirrors the arrangement of the previous series in the collection, with subseries as follows:
  MetroTech Center
  Vote of "No Confidence"
  Speeches & Symposia
  Publications & Notes
  Correspondence
  Clippings
  Polytechnic documents
  Memoranda, Newsletters, & Brochures
  MetroTech model
  Scope and Contents
  The additional material in this series was donated to the Poly Archives by Virginia Bugliarello on October 24, 2013. Some of the material was integrated into existing series within the collection, including Speeches & Symposia, Publications & Manuscripts, Correspondence, Clippings, and Photographs. The remainder of the additional material, which could not be integrated due to physical limitations, is in Addendum II.
  Virginia Bugliarello's donation letter for this additional material is in the first box (Box 50) of Addendum II.
  - Subseries A: MetroTech Center, 1984-2004; 7153
    - Donation letter to Virginia Bugliarello, 2013 October 24; 7163 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence- George Bugliarello, 1984-1989; 7164 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence- MetroTech and donations, 1978-1998; 7165 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Speeches- Bugliarello, 1989; 7166 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - MetroTech proposal, agreements, and fact sheet, 1989-2007; 7167 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - MetroTech golden shovel invitation, 1989; 7168 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - MetroTech publications, 1992-1999; 7169 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - N.Y. Building Congress Leadership Awards and Park Ranking Index, 1993; 7170 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - MetroTech Case Study, 2004; 7171 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Notes- MetroTech: NY Response to Silicon Valley, undated; 7172 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - MetroTech and Tenopolis, 1989-1990; 7173 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Clippings- MetroTech, 1989-1997; 7174 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Clippings- Oversize, 1985-1990; 7175 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Newspapers, 1982-1989; 7176 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Vote of "No Confidence", 1989; 7159
    The folders follow the arrangement of the papers within an envelope labeled, "Vote of 'no confidence' 1989."
    - "A Caution on Unions", 1975; 7177 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1989; 7178 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Tuition Increase- Commentary and reports, 1989; 7179 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - "Resolution", undated; 7180 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda- Members of the Faculty and the Corporation, 1989; 7181 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - George Bugliarello's Remarks and Annual Report, 1988; 7182 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence- Regarding Governor Carey, 1974; 7183 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Speeches & Symposia, 7152
    - Commencement- First Year for Polytechnic Institute of New York (PINY), 1974; 7184 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Oral Statement by George Bugliarello before the Subcommittee on HUD, 1989 May 4; 7185 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Caledonian Hospital, 1989 June 2; 7186 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - The Reward of Innovation, 1990 January 5; 7187 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Commencement Address, Milwaukee School of Engineering, 1991 November 23; 7188 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Confidential: I.O.R.C. Position Paper (draft, by Bugliarello), circa 1975; 7189 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Regional Role of Engineering College Conference, 1973; 7190 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Cornell Seminar, undated; 7191 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Introduction to Newcomen Society, 1975 September 18; 7192 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Interview with Jeff Newman, 1983; 7193 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Inauguration Speech Materials, 1955-1974; 7194 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Humanity 3000: Symposium No. 1 Proceedings, 2000; 7195 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - The University: How Neutral is Neutral?, 1975 January 26; 7196 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Third Annual Clinical Engineering Symposium and Technical Exhibition, 1987 October 7-9; 7197 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Speech notes, 1973, 1973; undated; 7198 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Speech notes, undated; 7232 (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Subseries D: Publications & Notes, 7157
    - L'Aerazione dello Stramazzo Tipo, 1951; 7199 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - The Peripheral Plasma Layer in Pulsatile Flow in Hollow Glass Fibers, 1969; 7200 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - The New Engineering Education, 1973; 7201 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - LC Science Tracer Bulletin, 1975; 7202 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Peace, Welfare and Security for Mankind through Educations, 1975; 7203 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - The City as an Adaptive Entity, 1999; 7204 (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Technological Innovation, undated; 7205 (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - Technological Forecasting, 1973; 7206 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Toward a Check List for Human Factors in Environmental Engineering, undated; 7207 (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Prospectives in Bioengineering Research for Civil Engineers, undated; 7208 (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Stochastic Simulation of Convective Diffusion in the Axial Plasmatic Gaps of Capillaries, 1966; 7209 (Box 51, Folder 34)
    - Publications not by Bugliarello, 1962-1984; 7233 (Box 51, Folder 35)
    - Notes- Poly Endowment, undated; 7234 (Box 51, Folder 36)
    - Notes- Nassau County Dinners, undated; 7235 (Box 51, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous drafts and notes, undated; 7210 (Box 51, Folder 38)
    - Comments on conference, undated; 7211 (Box 51, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1974, 7212 (Box 51, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated; 7213 (Box 51, Folder 41)
    - Notes, undated; 7236 (Box 51, Folder 42)
    - Notes, undated; 7237 (Box 51, Folder 43)
    - Notes, undated; 7238 (Box 51, Folder 44)
    - Notes, undated; 7239 (Box 51, Folder 45)
    - Notebooks, 1956; 7240 (Box 51, Folder 46)
  - Subseries E: Correspondence, 7156
    - Correspondence, 1955, 7214 (Box 51, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, 1966, 7215 (Box 51, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1970s, 1971-1979; 7216 (Box 51, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence, 1981, 7217 (Box 51, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence, 1990s, 1991-1999; 7218 (Box 51, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, 2007, 7219 (Box 51, Folder 52)
  - Subseries F: Clippings, 7154
    - Clippings, 1970s, 1973-1977; 7220 (Box 51, Folder 53)
    - Clippings, Poly-Long Island, 1975-1979; 7221 (Box 51, Folder 54)
    - Clippings, 1980s, 1982-1989; 7222 (Box 51, Folder 55)
    - Clippings, 1990s, 1990-1999; 7223 (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Clippings, 2000s, 2007-2011; 7224 (Box 51, Folder 57)
  - Subseries G: Polytechnic documents, 7241
    - Student aid grant summary and Expenditure report, 1973; 7242 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Application for reserach grant, 1965; 7243 (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1975; undated; 7244 (Box 51, Folder 60)
  - Subseries H: Memorada, Newsletters, & Brochures, 7155
    - Memorada and News Releases, 1990-1994; 7225 (Box 41, Folder 61)
    - Newsletters, 1974-1989; 7226 (Box 51, Folder 62)
    - Conference Programs, 1960s, 1965-1969; 7227 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Conference Programs, 1970s, 1972-1977; 7228 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Conference Programs, 1980s, 1987-1999; 1987-1989; 7229 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Polytechnic Brochures and Commencement Programs, 1975-2013; 7230 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Brochures and Publications, 1966-1997; 7231 (Box 54)
  - Subseries I: MetroTech model, 7162
    The MetroTech model was commissioned by Forest City Ratner by Real Models, Inc. Atlanta. It is on loan from Virigina Bugliarello.
  - Subseries J: Polytechnic Commencement robe, undated; 7416 (Box 55)
- Series XIII: 2022 Accretion, 1971-1980
  These items are a 2022 accretion to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello and consist of papers as well as publications written or edited by Bugliarello. These items had been pulled from the collection and set aside as possible duplicates. Upon closer inspection, unique items were identified, resulting in this accretion. This accretion is located on bay 28, shelf 5E.
  - Sub-series A: Inauguration, 1974-1975
    - Inauguration (I), 1974-1975 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Inauguration (II), 1975 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series B: Publications, 1971-1980
    - Science Advice to the President edited by George Bugliarello, et al., 1980 (Box 57, Item 1)
    - Women in Engineering: Bridging the Gap Between Society and Technology edited by George Bugliarello, et al, 1971 (Box 57, Item 2)